we are extraordinary. We can do more. And another thing for Malawi, and not just Malawi but other countries: The laws which are there, you know how a law is not a law until it is enforced? The law which has just recently passed and the laws that in other countries have been there, they need to be publicized at the local level, at the community level, where girls' issues are very striking. Girls face issues, difficult issues, at the community level every day. So if these young girls know that there are laws that protect them, they will be able to stand up and defend themselves because they will know that there is a law that protects them. And another thing I would say is that girls' voices and women's voices are beautiful, they are there, but we cannot do this alone. Male advocates, they have to jump in, to step in and work together. It's a collective work. What we need is what girls elsewhere need: good education, and above all, not to marry whilst 11. And furthermore, I know that together, we can transform the legal, the cultural and political framework that denies girls of their rights. I am standing here today and declaring that we can end child marriage in a generation. This is the moment where a girl and a girl, and millions of girls worldwide, will be able to say, "I will marry when I want." (Applause) Thank you. (Applause)
nous sommes exceptionnelles. On peut faire davantage. Et de plus, au Malawi, et non seulement au Malawi, mais dans d'autres pays : la législation qui existe, savez-vous qu'une loi ne l'est pas vraiment si elle n'est pas appliquée? La loi qui vient d'être adoptée et les lois qui existent dans d'autres pays, il faut les faire connaître au niveau local, au niveau de la communauté, où les enjeux à l'égard des filles sont frappants. Elles font face à des défis très difficiles dans la communauté chaque jour. Si ces jeunes filles connaissent l'existence des lois pour les protéger, elles seront capables de se défendre, parce qu'elles savent qu'une loi les protègent. Je veux dire une autre chose : les voix des filles et des femmes sont belles, elles sont là, mais on ne peut pas le faire tout seul. Les hommes doivent défendre, ils doivent participer, intervenir, pour travailler ensemble. Il s'agit d'un effort collectif. On veut ce que les filles ont besoin partout : une bonne formation et surtout le choix de ne pas se marier à 11 ans. Et de plus, je sais qu'ensemble, on peut transformer le cadre légal, culturel et politique qui nie les droits aux filles. Aujourd'hui je suis devant vous et j'affirme qu'en une seule génération, on peut mettre fin au mariage d'enfants. C'est le moment quand une fille et des millions de filles partout dans le monde, disent : « Je me marie quand je veux. » (Applaudissements) Merci. (Applaudissements)